<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stack overflow on the fØund4ŧ¹°n</title>
    <link>https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/tags/stack-overflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stack overflow on the fØund4ŧ¹°n</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/tags/stack-overflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shittification of the internetz - The toxic thingy Stack Overflow became and why it is so annoying to even ask on Crap Overload</title>
      <link>https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/posts/2023_02_02_shittification_of_the_internetz-the_toxic_thingy_stack_overflow_became_and_why_it_is_so_annoying_to_even_ask_on_crap_overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/posts/2023_02_02_shittification_of_the_internetz-the_toxic_thingy_stack_overflow_became_and_why_it_is_so_annoying_to_even_ask_on_crap_overload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;stackoverflow----you-want-help--you-get-downvotes&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; -  you want help ? you get downvotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow people might be attracted by Stack Overflow ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maybe because it&amp;rsquo;s mostly top-ranked by Search Engines,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maybe because sometimes it really helps ,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maybe it keeps people in business that should better do stuff without brain-usage or something where they cannot harm people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But over the years it has become a dirt-pool &lt;strong&gt;that is quicker in instant-downvoting and duplicate-flagging&lt;/strong&gt; than answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/posts/2023_02_02_shittification_of_the_internetz-the_toxic_thingy_stack_overflow_became_and_why_it_is_so_annoying_to_even_ask_on_crap_overload/imgs/so_keyboard_Nisarg_Shah.twitter.Nisarg259.png&#34;
	width=&#34;662&#34;
	height=&#34;463&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Stack Overflow Keyboard  Screenshot from Twitter timeline of Nisarg259&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;142&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;343px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that is what happens when platforms tend to be &amp;ldquo;up/down-vote&amp;rdquo;-style places full of  Mr./Mrs.-always-right &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;people that post and are downvoted just because of &amp;ldquo;how the answer was &amp;quot; just leave or don&amp;rsquo;t post anymore, leaving the self-confirming &amp;ldquo;crowd&amp;rdquo; to play their toxic games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniquebusinessmodels.substack.com/p/31-how-does-stack-overflow-make-money&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;in fact the knowledge collected is turned into $$$ by StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I_ZK0t9-llo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;There is a youtube Video that has some painful examples of what is going on over there&lt;/a&gt; , stories where people are &lt;strong&gt;rewarded to remove their questions&lt;/strong&gt; (WTF!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the description there is a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; true statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stack Overflow culture &lt;strong&gt;needs to be fixed&lt;/strong&gt;. The overall &lt;strong&gt;gatekeeping &amp;amp; elitism&lt;/strong&gt; in computer science &amp;amp; programming - as a whole - needs to be fixed. &lt;strong&gt;I just see it more on Stack Overflow than anywhere else&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the internet is full of threads that ask why a bunch of bullies is dominating on SO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to sum it up &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/AskProgramming/comments/9pgc1a/why_is_asking_on_stackoverflow_so_horrible/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;there is a reddit that says it all &lt;/a&gt;, so here are some quotes ( of more than 1 user ) from that thread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In return for my technical question, I get what &lt;strong&gt;amounts to a colonoscopy, by what appear to be 14 year old &amp;ldquo;engineers&amp;rdquo;, who racked up internet points asserting wrong information with brazen confidence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is everyone &lt;strong&gt;responding in underhanded, condescending tone, under a thin veil of technical clarification?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that people &lt;strong&gt;who don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer, nor care to even understand the question, need to comment, then upvote their incorrect comments, all meanwhile downvoting my question?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..  &lt;strong&gt;asking a question on SO is equivalent to giving up whatever dignity you have, or be downvoted&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;no logical reason&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SO has always had a problem with toxicity. I think the &lt;strong&gt;main reason for this is that it&amp;rsquo;s not actually a Q&amp;amp;A platform. It&amp;rsquo;s a wiki under the guise of a Q&amp;amp;A platform&lt;/strong&gt;. This explains why people can edit your posts and why ++SO explicitly encourages users to post questions that they already have the answer to**.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SO doesn&amp;rsquo;t want people to post questions asking for help. They want people to create Q&amp;amp;A-style wiki pages to add to their curated collection of knowledge. If your question doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a good answer of general use to the populous, then it&amp;rsquo;ll be downvoted and closed because it&amp;rsquo;s not useful to them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unfortunately, people innocently try to get help on the site and are subsequently berated and their questions torn apart&lt;/strong&gt;. SO has tried to address this issue, but it seems that they haven&amp;rsquo;t made any progress.
&lt;strong&gt;The first rule of SO is NEVER EVER ask questions on it. It&amp;rsquo;ll get down voted and marked as duplicate immediately.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a great reference. Absolutely terrible source of help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/csharp/comments/tf7ec3/stackoverflow_has_too_many_selfrighteous/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A reddit has some user-horror-stories and a lot of criticism&lt;/a&gt; about the self-righteous moderators and that they act as if they were the north-korean authorities, here are some excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stackoverflow lives from the contribution of thousands contributors, &lt;strong&gt;but is controlled by a small band of moderators who have dictatorship like powers&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; Of course, it is good that Stackoverflow tries to enforce a certain level of quality for its content, but having this &amp;ldquo;police&amp;rdquo; punishing others leads to the same problem like any other police has: &lt;strong&gt;They feel they are omnipotent and always right, even if they are wrong&lt;/strong&gt;. I wish Stackoverflow would be more supporting of their content provider and help them to improve their contribution &lt;strong&gt;instead of removing content with wrong justifications and no easy way to challenge that&lt;/strong&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One tool these &lt;strong&gt;moderators like to use to suppress a discussion&lt;/strong&gt; is to &lt;strong&gt;mark a question as duplicate, which means the question/answers get closed, no further discussion is possible&lt;/strong&gt;. They &lt;strong&gt;just pretend that a many year old question sounds similar&lt;/strong&gt; . The worst example I have seen: A question asked why he gets a null reference in a specific WPF situation. The &lt;strong&gt;question got marked as duplicate&lt;/strong&gt;, because someone had posted 100 reasons why a null reference can happen, &lt;strong&gt;but with zero relevance for WPF&lt;/strong&gt;. There was a good reason why the null reference exception happened in this particular situation, &lt;strong&gt;but it was no longer possible to add an answer&lt;/strong&gt; explaining why the problem happen. And &lt;strong&gt;normal mortals have no chance to overturn the duplicate decision&lt;/strong&gt;, for that you need to have a tons of points on Stackoverflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. problem started when my answer got deleted with the reason &amp;quot; Code plagiarised without attribution&amp;rdquo;, which was wrong in my opinion . Since my original answer got deleted, you cannot see in that link, that&amp;rsquo;s how censorship works on Stackoverflow. I wrote all the content myself, except at the very end where I pasted some WPF source code. I made it clear that this was not my code and where it is coming from&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;clearly stated that I could not write this code and that it is WPF source code&lt;/strong&gt;. How can this be plagiarism ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using Stackoverflow since many years but I really could not figure out how to appeal this decision. So I tried to raise the issue on Meta: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/416605/how-to-get-an-answer-deleted-by-a-moderator-because-of-code-plagiarized-withou&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/416605/how-to-get-an-answer-deleted-by-a-moderator-because-of-code-plagiarized-withou&lt;/a&gt;. I did this reluctantly due to my earlier experience with self-righteous moderators, who usually react aggressively when anyone dares to mention that there was a problem on Stackoverflow. I wonder if they feel personally questioned and go into defense/attack mode automatically &amp;hellip; got there comments like &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t know how to quote and cite your sources when writing any professional document? I find that hard to believe.&amp;rdquo; Well, the truth is that I have never written a professional document citing sources. As it is common on Meta, &lt;strong&gt;many commenters do not consider if the case presented has any merit&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e. I did write in my answer that it is not my code and where I got it from). Instead they like to &lt;strong&gt;attack the person who dares to question their actions&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip; To &lt;strong&gt;suppress any further discussion&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;moderators&lt;/strong&gt; used their preferred weapon and &lt;strong&gt;marked my Meta post as duplicate, even the other question had completely different circumstances&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they didn&amp;rsquo;t like me raising my question on Meta, &lt;strong&gt;they also marked my original question as duplicate&lt;/strong&gt;. Please note that my &lt;strong&gt;question had gone already through a review process and was accepted as proper. Only after I raised it on Meta my original question was closed&lt;/strong&gt; because of &amp;ldquo;This question needs details or clarity&amp;rdquo;. Again, &lt;strong&gt;no easy option to appeal the decision&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;only action they allow is that I change my question&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the replies, users have &lt;strong&gt;more horrific stories&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. once asked a question &lt;strong&gt;that took hours to write and referenced 5 different approaches to the problem&lt;/strong&gt;, and all I got was a &lt;strong&gt;downvote without explanation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stack overflow has at this point &lt;strong&gt;deleted as much useful content as it currently contains&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip; there were always attitude issues amongst the power users, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect anything less, &lt;strong&gt;but when they started getting militant about the definition of subjective and combining loosely related topics as duplicate&lt;/strong&gt; then later *&lt;strong&gt;deleting the question the defined as the original as low quality&lt;/strong&gt; it started to go downhill pretty fast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SO has become a place where dictatorship is rife, people are unfriendly and there is too much moderation going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StackOverflow has become a slightly less spammy version of Experts Exchange. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s woefully out of date on most things, gives bad and/or conflicting advice on everything else&lt;/strong&gt;, and generally has become a useless pile of junk. And most of the reason is what you&amp;rsquo;ve described here. The &lt;strong&gt;moderator fiefdoms result in petty turf wars and bad comments rise to the top because of political reasons&lt;/strong&gt; rather than technical ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Someone read your answer&amp;rdquo;, no they did not read it, they &lt;strong&gt;just posted competitive answer and after they realized they need a little bit more reputation&lt;/strong&gt; (for what?!) and my answer is already upvoted (more important to them then to me), they &lt;strong&gt;started plagiarism story&lt;/strong&gt;. Couple hour later, &lt;strong&gt;moderator that also did not check ANYTHING (answer, profile, links&amp;hellip;) deleted my post&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no reason for any kind of &amp;ldquo;we are just trying to protect our company&amp;rdquo; action, but on the contrary: people are decreasing SO reputation because they need just to distinguish themselves, not to help people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fyi Stack overflow is really old &amp;hellip;  Is &lt;strong&gt;still uses Windows Server and MSSQL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-is-bad-about-Stack-Overflow&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;On Quora .. different place , same story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To also cite the &amp;ldquo;highlights&amp;rdquo;(dark spots) of SO from there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s the dumbest web-site I’ve ever seen. They should help people but they kept closing my questions for no reason, even banned me from asking more.&lt;/strong&gt; I am asking BECAUSE I am not a pro. I always tried to be concise and clear, &lt;strong&gt;their stupid bots just closed many of my questions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;voting system on Stack Overflow is that it penalizes users&lt;/strong&gt;. It only takes &lt;strong&gt;a few negative votes to get you banned from asking questions&lt;/strong&gt;, taking part on the platform. In my experience, &lt;strong&gt;rarely do downvotes get removed&lt;/strong&gt; from questions that have been improved through editing. &lt;strong&gt;Even &amp;ldquo;deleting&amp;rdquo; questions will not remove their negative score on one&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; ** the strict gamification** of Stackoverflow, &lt;strong&gt;turning users into winners and losers&lt;/strong&gt;, creates an &lt;strong&gt;overall unwelcoming, precarious attitude towards beginner programmers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;it’s sh*t&lt;/strong&gt;, and I will use the word &lt;strong&gt;totalitarian&lt;/strong&gt;, Stack Overflow (regarding its coding forums side) &lt;strong&gt;is a totalitarian place&lt;/strong&gt;, the totalitarianism is &lt;strong&gt;first handled by the people who run SO&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-is-bad-about-Stack-Overflow&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;In the mentioned Quora thread&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/profile/Quora-Question-Details-Bot&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt; &lt;code&gt;Quora Question Details Bot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; seems to have a good sense of humour, since it replies to the Question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;What is bad about Stack Overflow?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the balls-of-steel answer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;...if you&#39;re using their service.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/posts/2023_02_02_shittification_of_the_internetz-the_toxic_thingy_stack_overflow_became_and_why_it_is_so_annoying_to_even_ask_on_crap_overload/imgs/quora-bot-hates-stack-overflow.png&#34;
	width=&#34;819&#34;
	height=&#34;179&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Stack-overflow-fake-programmers image by industan.com &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;457&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;1098px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-statement&#34;&gt;Final statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/223176/how-to-exit-stack-overflow&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;In the end there is no need to delete your Crap-Overload account, just don&amp;rsquo;t ask if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to loose your dignity  , there is even an answer how to log out :D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to be honest : &lt;strong&gt;Windows Server and MSSQL Stack&lt;/strong&gt; in 2022 ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They could just ask on their platform why and how to not do that ..
Basically when reading CVE&amp;rsquo;s on a regular basis , nobody should put personal data there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://the-foundation.is-a-p.ro.eu.org/posts/2023_02_02_shittification_of_the_internetz-the_toxic_thingy_stack_overflow_became_and_why_it_is_so_annoying_to_even_ask_on_crap_overload/imgs/so_fake_programmer-techindustan.com.png&#34;
	width=&#34;651&#34;
	height=&#34;347&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Stack-overflow-fake-programmers image by industan.com &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;187&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;450px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description> 
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>